

JAVIER PEYRIERE

DATA ANALYST - SCIENTIST - CONSULTANT

◆ PARIS, FRANCE +33 (0)786497940

Looking for a hands-on experience with handling different Data End to End Projects as internship or fixed-termed contract.

• DETAILS •

Paris, France +33 (0)786497940 javier.peyriere@gmail.com

o LINKS o

<u>LinkedIn</u> gitHub 1st project

o SKILLS o

Adaptability - Collaboration

Critical & Analytical Thinking

Problem Solving - Business Acumen

Creativity - Curiosity

• HARD SKILLS •

Python - pandas -matplotlib - seaborn -

git - gitHub - Deepnote

SQL - MySQL - Tableau

Statistical Analysis - Data Interpretation

Machine Learning Knowledge

Web scrapping – APIs - BigQuery

○ LANGUAGES ○

Trilingual French, Spanish, English

• OTHER COURSES •

2023 : INRIA-FUN, MOOC Python : des fondamentaux aux concepts avancés du langage

Schlumberger internal trainings (1 per year): Management (1, 2, 3, 4) - incl. HR & Finance-, QHSE (1, 2, 3), Sales (1, 2), Successful Bidding, Negotiations, Technical Courses

2006: Price Increase Seminar-INSEAD

○ HOBBIES ○

Piano, Guitar, Marathon Running, Rugby Union

PROFILE

25 years of International experience for a Global Group, a mid-size entity & an SME. Strong experience in using Data Analysis & Interpretation, Data Acquisition and QC, recently focusing on Data Analytics and Artificial Intelligence.

★ DATA PROJECTS

IRONHACK:, Paris February 2024 — May 2024: 'Defining the target':

End to End Project defining a target company for acquisition: Data collected, intensive API & web scrapping, data cleaned and wrangled, exploratory data analysis -EDA, feature engineering, pre-processing, model selected, evaluated and data visualized

'Vanguard Training Project': Mid Term Project, EDA and Data Cleaned, Performance Metrics Hypothesis tested, Experiment Evaluation done, visualization through Tableau

SEAOWL, Paris January 2020 — September 2023

Achieved a high ratio of bidding success and efficient set up of the entities, through data analysis and the use of data for the projection and evaluation of the business

SOCOTEC & SICA, Paris March 2012 — December 2019

Setup of the database and internal ERP for the worldwide inspections, defining the KPIs and data to monitor and use for sales and operations.

SCHLUMBERGER, Paris March 2000 — March 2012

Set up overperforming operating entities and strong bid success rate through data use and analysis of data (Operations, Sales, Marketing): in particular for service strategies for operations implementation, pricing strategies, or tendering (Russia, Congo, France, UK). Data Acquisition, Data QC and interpretation (UK, Congo, Norway).

EDUCATION

RCNP Lev. 6 in Data Analytics – Al Development, IronHack, Paris February 2024 — May 2024 MSc in Exploration Geophysics, Curtin University, Perth January 1998 — December 1998 DEA, Geomorphology - Remote Sensing, Paris VII, September 1996 — September 1997

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Managing Director at SEAOWL, Paris January 2020 — September 2023

Jan 21-Sep 23: <u>Managing Director</u> SeaOwl Marine; Paris-Brest, France: record years, >20M€, 8 offshore vessels, >150 persons

Jan 20-Dec 20: <u>Managing Director</u> SeaOwl ES; Paris-Pau, France, Covid challenges, kept the 20M€ level and > 250 persons

VP Operations & Sales at SOCOTEC O&G & SICA, Paris March 2012 — December 2019

Mar-16-Dec 19: <u>VP Operations & Sales</u>; Paris, France: record years 25MUSD agglomerated, > 150 people full time.

Mar-12-Mar 16: SICA VP Operations; Paris, France: from 6 to 12MUSD, 100 people.

SCHLUMBERGER March 2000 — March 2012

Nov-10-Mar-12: <u>Business Development Manager</u>; Paris, France: 75 MUSD portfolio.

Aug 09-Nov-10: <u>Operations Manager</u>; Tyumen, Russian Federation: Looking after 10 business units. Record year 65 MUSD, 400 persons

May 07-Jul 09: <u>Country Manager</u>; Pointe-Noire, Congo (Brazzaville): from 25 to 50 MUSD. 100 persons over 3 countries.

Jan 06-April 07: Account Manager; Aberdeen, UK: Portfolio of 20 MUSD.

June 03- Dec 05: Field Service Manager; Pau, France: from 3 to 8 MUSD.30 persons.

Mar 00– May 03: <u>Field Engineer</u>; Norway; Denmark; Congo: Technical/ Data acquisition and Data Interpretation for wells of 1 to 2 MUSD